(BOTH GRUNTING)
Come on!
No fastidies.
You're Hawkeye!
Eres Ojo de Halcón.
En episodios anteriores
I love you, Dad.
Te quiero, papá.
(CHUCKLES) I love you more.
Yo a ti más.
Call me when you get home? I love you.
Llamad cuando lleguéis a casa. Os quiero.
Armand Duquesne was found dead in his home last night.
Duquesne fue hallado muerto anoche en su casa.
-Yeah. -These two events have officials wondering
-Sí. -Tras lo ocurrido, la policía se pregunta
if indeed, the Ronin has returned to New York City and what he may do next.
si es cierto que Ronin ha vuelto y cuál podría ser su siguiente paso.
-(KATE GRUNTS) -(ELEANOR YELPS)
Jack is hiding something, Mom.
Jack oculta algo, mamá.
Don't you think it's a little strange that the same night his uncle threatens you,
¿No te parece un poco raro que la misma noche que su tío te amenaza,
he ends up murdered by sword?
aparezca muerto con heridas de espada?
-Kate Bishop is guy in costume. -Who are you talking about?
-Kate Bishop es el tío del disfraz. -¿Quién es esa?
(GROANS)
We have them...
Los tenemos.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
TEACHER: And listen.
Escuchad.
BOY: Hey!
¡Oye!
(VOICES FADE)
(INAUDIBLE)
Abrid el libro por la página...
Palabras...
Maya... intérprete.
Presta aten...
(GIRL AND MAN LAUGHING)
(MOUTHING)
¿Qué ruido hace el cielo?
(WHISPERS) It's quiet like you.
Ninguno, como tú.
¿Qué ruido hacen los dragones?
-(GROWLS) -(LAUGHS)
¿Los dragones existen?
Um, no. Maybe they are,
Bueno, quizá.
but dragons live in a different world.
Pero viven en otro mundo.
¿Y si aprenden
a entrar en nuestro mundo?
Well, that would make them stronger.
Pues los haría más fuertes.
Creía que mi cole
era para niños como yo.
It's impossible.
Eso es imposible.
See, you are one of a kind.
Porque tú eres única.
Pero dijiste
que podíamos permitirnos un cole para niños sordos.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
But in the end, it'll be better for you.
Pero, a la larga, este será mejor para ti.
¿Tendré que dejar de signar?
No.
You have to learn to jump between two worlds.
Tendrás que aprender a vivir en los dos mundos.
¿Cómo?
Just by watching.
Observando.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CHILDREN EXCLAIM IN AWE)
INSTRUCTOR: All right, class. Water break.
Vale, clase. A beber agua.
Hey, be good in class today.
Oye, que vaya muy bien la clase de hoy.
But remember, for your match, it's more about speed than size.
Pero recuerda que es más importante ser rápida que ser grande.
Hmm? Uncle will take you home after class.
El tío te llevará a casa después de clase.
I'll see you tonight.
Nos vemos esta noche.
Vale, papá.
(MAN CHUCKLES)
Maya, you're up.
Maya, te toca.
And bow.
Saludaos.
Ready?
¿Listos?
Fight!
¡Pelead!
(CHILDREN EXCLAIMING)
(PUNK ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
-(WOMAN GRUNTS) -(GROANS)
(ENGINE SHUTS OFF)
(SWORDS CLASHING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
(MAN 1 GROANS)
(MAN 2 GRUNTING)
Vete, por favor.
No pienso dejarte.
(SNIFFLING)
Ya me he ido.
Vete...
...dragoncito.
Ojo de Halcón
MAN 1: You're like a pony, Hawkeye.
¿Te gusta el poni, Ojo de Halcón?
(MAN 1 LAUGHS)
MAN 2: Just keep going, and going, and going. I love it.
Eso es, dale, cabalga. Me encanta.
MAN 1: I love it, bro. Look at Hawkeye!
Me encanta, tío. Mirad a Ojo de Halcón.
-MAN 2: Where's your arrows now? -MAN 1: Pew, pew.
¿Dónde te has dejado las flechas?
Big, strong Hawkeye riding prony.
El gran Ojo de Halcón a lomos de un poni.
MAN 1: They should smile more. This is fun for us too, you know.
No sé por qué tienen esa cara, con lo divertido que es.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
-MAN 3: Again. Enrique, again, come on. -Great.
-Dale, Enrique, dale otra vez, venga. -Genial.
-MAN 2: Go get more quarters. -Yes.
-Ve a por más monedas. -Sí.
This is boring. Dmitri, let's play cards.
Me aburro. Dimitri, trae las cartas.
Seems like you're mad at me.
Te noto como enfadado conmigo.
I know it doesn't look like that,
Ya sé que ahora mismo no lo parece,
but you'd be lost without me, you realize that?
pero sin mí estarías perdido, que lo sepas.
I was about to clear your name from the suit,
Casi se tragan que no tenías nada que ver con el traje.
until you decided to crash through the skylight.
Hasta que has decidido caer del cielo.
-Oh. -Yeah.
Sí.
-(OBJECTS CLATTERING) -(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
-Bro! -Cálmate, bro. Cálmate. (SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
-Macho. -Cálmate, tío.
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
You good?
¿Todo bien?
I buy Imagine Dragons tickets for my girlfriend,
Le compré a mi novia entradas para ir a ver a Imagine Dragons,
as, like, early Christmas gift, right?
en plan regalo adelantado de Navidad.
-Mmm. That's so sweet. -Good, sweet.
-Qué detallazo. -Sí, un detallazo.
Then we had fight. You know what she said?
Pero hemos discutido y me ha dicho
She said that the tickets were gift, so she wants to bring her sister.
que como las entradas eran un regalo, se va con su hermana.
I mean, look on the bright side.
A ver, mira el lado bueno.
You don't have to go see Imagine Dragons.
Así no tienes que ir a ver a Imagine Dragons.
I love Imagine Dragons.
Me encanta Imagine Dragons.
Uh, she doesn't even like them, you know. She did this on purpose to hurt me.
A ella ni siquiera le gustan. Lo ha hecho para fastidiarme.
Look, I think you both owe apologies.
Creo que los dos os debéis una disculpa.
Tell her she hurt your feelings,
Dile que te ha hecho daño,
but apologize for pretending that that was a gift for her.
pero pídele perdón por colarle las entradas como un regalo.
Okay, wait, I need a pen. Just... Okay, okay? See you.
Vale, espera, voy a por un boli. ¿Vale? Ahora vengo.
Hmm. See? A little trust,
¿Ves? Un poco de confianza,
a little communicating, a little listening...
un poco de comunicación, de atención...
-What? -KATE: Basic human stuff.
-¿Qué? -Un mínimo de humanidad.
-You know what I think? -You know what I think? Hmm?
-¿Sabes qué creo? -¿Sabes qué creo yo?
I think you talk too much.
Que hablas demasiado.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
She always like this?
¿Es siempre así?
Maybe I rip out your throat. Hmm?
Igual podría rajarte el cuello.
(DOOR OPENS)
Or maybe she will.
O igual lo hace ella.
Who is she?
¿Quién es esa?
BARTON: Thank you.
Gracias.
Oh, uh, yeah. Sorry.
Ya, perdona.
Hard of hearing, not deaf.
Tengo problemas de audición, pero no soy sordo.
Oh, boy.
Ay, madre.
(GRUNTING)
More cookie, please. Thank you.
Más galletas, por favor. Gracias.
Uh...
Right, well, it's nice talking to you.
Vale, un placer charlar contigo.
She asked what you're doing here, Clint Barton.
Pregunta qué haces aquí, Clint Barton.
(BARTON CLEARS THROAT)
-Riding a unicorn. -Learning about trust.
-Montar en unicornio. -Aprendiendo a confiar.
KAZI: "You rely too much on technology."
"Dependes demasiado de la tecnología".
Well, my go-to weapon is two sticks and a string, so...
Bueno, llevo dos palos y una cuerda como arma, así que no...
-KAZI: No, she means your hearing aid. -BARTON: Ah.
Se refiere al audífono.
"You might find you're better off without it."
"Igual te iría mejor sin él".
Yeah, sometimes I think that very same thing.
Sí, a veces yo pienso lo mismo.
Now, the suit.
Volviendo al traje.
She put it on by accident.
La chica se lo puso por error.
She didn't know what it means.
No sabía lo que significaba.
She's not Ronin.
No es Ronin.
Look at her. She's nine.
Miradla, tiene nueve años.
And spoiled rotten.
Es una niña mimada.
KAZI: "She beat up a few of my guys
"Ha machacado a varios de mis hombres
"and then came running when you were in trouble.
"y ha venido a tu rescate".
"Seems like she's got something to do with it. "And just because she's not the Ronin doesn't mean that Ronin's not back."
"Me da que tiene algo que ver en esto.
"Que ella no sea Ronin no significa que Ronin no haya vuelto".
That's just a rumor.
Solo son rumores.
KAZI: "How do you know?"
"¿Cómo lo sabes?".
Because he's dead.
Porque está muerto.
KAZI: "So, who got him, then?"
"¿Quién acabó con él?".
(INAUDIBLE)
Viuda Negra.
"So Ronin is dead, and the person who killed him is dead.
"Así que Ronin está muerto y la persona que lo mató también.
"That's convenient. How do you know this?"
"Qué oportuno todo. ¿Cómo lo sabes?".
'Cause I was there.
Porque estuve allí.
KAZI: "You're lying."
"Mientes".
Okay, clearly this isn't working. Um...
Vale, está claro que esto no funciona.
If you have nothing to do with this,
Si no tienes nada que ver con esto,
then why did you put on this suit in the first place?
¿por qué te pusiste el traje?
(INAUDIBLE)
-(GRUNTS) -KAZI: Maya, no.
Maya, ¡no!
(CHOKING) Oh, God. I put that suit on because I didn't want
Me puse el traje porque no quería
anybody to know that I was at the auction, okay?
que nadie supiera que estaba en la subasta.
I didn't know what it was when I put it on, I swear.
No sabía lo que era cuando me lo puse, lo juro.
(COUGHING) I swear.
Lo juro.
-(COUGHS) -What are you doing?
¿Qué haces?
-Doesn't matter, okay? -BARTON: Listen to me.
-Da igual, ¿vale? -Escúchame.
Listen. No, now's not the time to be scared.
Escucha. Ahora no es momento de asustarse.
We're gonna get out of this.
Vamos a salir de esta.
You go back to living your life, I'll go back to my family.
Tú volverás a tu vida y yo volveré con mi familia.
You're gonna harness that over-confidence of yours, okay?
Ahora tienes que aprovechar tu exceso de confianza.
This ridiculous over-confidence, you remember that one?
Ese exceso de confianza tan grande que tienes, ¿estamos?
Okay? So wait for my signal.
Vale. A mi señal.
-You should... -KATE: How did you do that? Clint!
-Deberías... -¿Cómo lo has hecho? ¡Clint!
KAZI: Go help Maya, all right?
¡Ayudad a Maya!
Bring him back alive.
¡Lo quiero con vida!
Damn it!
¡Mierda!
Oh, man, it'd be really nice to know how you did that, Clint.
Estaría muy bien saber cómo has hecho eso, Clint.
Clint?
¿Clint?
IVAN: Hawkeye, come out and play.
Ojo de Halcón, sal a jugar.
Come out and play.
Sal a jugar.
IVAN: Look over there. Spread out.
Mirad por allí. Separaos.
(MEN SHOUTING, GRUNTING)
KAZI: Don't shoot! They want him alive, you idiot!
¡No dispares! ¡Lo quieren vivo, idiota!
(GRUNTS)
(MUFFLED RINGING)
(GROANS)
KAZI: Hey, hey, hey, hey!
¡Oye!
You're not going anywhere.
Tú de aquí no te mueves.
-(GRUNTS) -(GASPS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(MEN YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH CONTINUE GRUNTING)
(KAZI YELLS)
(YELLS)
(PANTING)
I was doing fine.
Me las apaño bien.
Okay.
Vale.
My hearing aid's smashed.
Me ha roto el audífono.
Come on, we gotta go.
Venga, hay que largarse.
But that girl still has my bow.
Pero la tía esa me ha quitado el arco.
We need a car.
Necesitamos un coche.
Oh, can we take this one?
¿Podemos coger este?
Man, this thing's beautiful.
Tío, es precioso.
-(GRUNTS) -(WINDOW SHATTERS)
I'm not smashin' a '72 Challenger. Come on.
No voy a cargarme un Challenger del 72. Venga ya.
Youth.
Esta juventud...
Let's go.
Vamos.
Yes, boss.
Sí, señor.
Hey, get over here, I need you to drive.
Ven aquí, conduces tú.
-What? I don't know how to drive. -Come over here.
-¿Qué? No sé conducir. -Ven aquí.
(MUFFLED) No, you, you drive. I shoot.
No, conduces tú. Yo disparo.
I'm not hearing you. You drive, okay?
No oigo nada. Conduces tú, ¿vale?
-(WINDOW SHATTERS) -(YELLS)
Come on. Come on!
¡Venga!
-KAZI: Ivan, come with me. -Let's go, let's go!
-Ivan, conmigo. -¡Vamos!
KAZI: Tomás, go with Maya.
Tomás, ve con Maya.
(MEN GRUNTING)
-MAN 1: Watch out! -MAN 2: Go, go!
-¡Cuidado! -¡Vamos!
MAN 3: Let's go! Let's go!
¡Vamos!
-BARTON: How many we got? -Four!
-¿Cuántos son? -¡Cuatro!
Yo, get in front of 'em! Get in front of 'em!
Tío, ¡ponte delante de ellos!
-(KATE YELLS) -BARTON: Hang on.
Cuidado.
-(KATE GRUNTS) -(HORNS HONKING)
BARTON: Wait, wait, wait. We're out of the regular arrows.
Espera, no nos quedan flechas normales.
What do you mean, we're... Oh, my God, trick arrows?
¿Cómo que...? Ay, madre, ¿son flechas truco?
Definitely not this one...
Esta, ni hablar.
-Don't say definitely like that. -Not this one.
-Lo de "ni hablar" sobraba. -Ni esta.
-This is too dangerous. -This one fine?
-Esta es demasiado peligrosa. -¿Y esta?
-I'm using this one. -Hey, be careful.
-Uso esta. -Ve con cuidado.
-I was born careful. -They're not regular arrows.
-Siempre voy con cuidado. -No son flechas normales.
Kate.
-KATE: Eenie, meenie, miney... -Got you. Come on, come on.
-Pito, pito... -Los tenemos. Venga.
Mo.
...gorgorito.
It's growing.
Se extiende.
Play-Doh arrow?
¿Es plastilina?
-Put wiper. -Come on.
-Pon los limpias. -Venga.
Ugh! I can't see nothing!
¡No veo nada!
Hit their wheels with the putty arrow.
Lanza una flecha masilla a las ruedas.
Oh. Great idea. I'll do that as soon as you label these damn things.
Buena idea. Lo haré en cuanto etiquetes las flechas.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
This'd be a lot easier if we were facing...
Sería mucho más fácil si los tuviéramos...
It'd be easier if we were facing the other way.
Sería más fácil si los tuviéramos de cara.
Yeah, just a... Hey, we're communicating!
Sí, pero... Anda, hay comunicación.
Hang on.
Agárrate.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BEEPS, EXPLODES)
(MEN EXCLAIM)
Holy...
Madre...
(SCREAMS)
There are four arrows more dangerous than that one?
¿Y hay cuatro flechas más peligrosas que esa?
A plunger arrow? What is the trick? That it's completely useless?
¿Una flecha desatascador? ¿Qué chorrada es esa?
-(TIRES SCREECHING) -(KATE GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
-Look out! -Watch it, moron!
-Cuidado. -¡Gilipollas!
Merry Christmas!
¡Feliz Navidad!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Please be a good one. Please be a good one.
Por favor, que sea buena.
(MEN PANTING)
What the hell is that one called?
¿Cómo narices se llama esa?
-Sorry, Santa. -(KATE GRUNTS)
Perdona, Santa.
BARTON: Kate.
Kate.
Here, acid arrows.
Toma, flechas ácido.
Drop the stoplights.
Tira los semáforos.
(GRUNTING, PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
BARTON: Kate, get in!
Kate, ¡entra!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
KATE: I'll take that, thank you.
Me lo quedo, gracias.
-(GRUNTS) -(YELLS)
(COUGHS)
BARTON: And the Challenger gets totaled anyway.
Al final nos hemos cargado el Challenger.
Now I really can't see. Thank you.
Ahora sí que no veo nada. Gracias.
-Wait. Hang on, hang on. -(EXCLAIMS)
Cuidado.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What is he doing?
¿Qué hace?
He's gonna crash into us.
Estamparse contra nosotros.
Here, take out that truck.
Toma, tumba el camión.
Aim high. Bring the arrow down on him.
Dispara arriba.
Para que le dé a él al bajar.
What's the plan? This is just a normal arrow.
¿Cuál es el plan? Porque me has dado una flecha normal.
I have no idea what you're saying, just gonna assume you're on board.
No te oigo, pero daré por hecho que estás de acuerdo.
On my mark. Ready?
A mi señal. ¿Lista?
Shoot up.
Dispara.
Kazi...
(GASPS)
That was amazing!
¡Qué pasada!
Take this. Cover me.
Toma. Cúbreme.
A USB arrow? What am I supposed to do with this?
¿Una flecha USB? ¿Qué quieres que haga con esto?
God, I hope he's got a dongle arrow to make this useful.
No le veo sentido sin un ordenador de por medio.
Don't move!
¡No os mováis!
You do not wanna see what this arrow does!
¡No os va a hacer ninguna gracia lo que hace esta flecha!
Trust me.
Creedme.
(SHOUTS IN RUSSIAN)
Follow me.
¡Sígueme!
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
KATE: Whoo-hoo!
Whoa! (GRUNTS)
Damn it. Come on, let's go!
Mierda. ¡Venga, vamos!
KATE: Now I get the whole plunger arrow thing.
Ya le veo la utilidad a la flecha desatascador.
(BOTH GROAN)
Oh, we gotta walk the dog.
Hay que sacar al perro.
You're not wrong...
Es verdad...
He's been cooped up all day.
Lleva todo el día sin salir.
Not quite sure how long a dog can--
No sé cuánto aguanta un perro sin...
...call yourself one of the world's greatest archers.
...que eres una de las mejores arqueras del mundo.
Oh, my God, do you really think so?
Dios, ¿lo dices en serio?
I wasn't sure how I'd do under all that pressure...
La verdad, no sabía qué tal se me daría bajo presión.
Probably should walk the dog. Don't you think?
Habrá que sacar al perro. ¿No te parece?
-Been cooped up all day. -(KATE CHUCKLES)
Lleva todo el día sin salir.
(FATHER CHRISTMAS PLAYING)
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUFFLED) Hey, Clint.
Hola, Clint.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
-Hey, hey, babe. -NATHANIEL: Hi, Daddy.
-Hola, cariño. -Hola, papá.
BARTON: Hey, listen, I can't really talk right now,
Oye, ahora mismo no puedo hablar,
uh, 'cause look... Maybe...
porque igual...
Do you have time to text? Can you text?
¿Puedes mandarme un mensaje? ¿Te va bien?
-Can you text me? -Clint, Clint, Clint.
-¿Me mandas un mensaje? -Clint.
BARTON: What?
¿Qué?
Niño pequeño
Nathaniel? Nathaniel, what are you...
¿Nathaniel? Nathaniel, ¿qué haces...?
What are you doin', buddy?
¿Qué haces, campeón?
Is everything okay? Where's Mama?
¿Va todo bien? ¿Y mamá?
NATHANIEL: She's still asleep.
Sigue durmiendo.
I'm so bored.
Me aburro mogollón.
Look, there's a... there might be a little delay, buddy.
Te oigo con un poco de retraso, peque.
Están todos durmiendo y se aburre
It's kind of a bad connection.
Hay poca cobertura.
(STUTTERS) You're bored.
Ah, que te aburres.
(CHUCKLES)
You're the early bird. Hey, bud, I miss you.
Es que eres muy madrugador. Oye, te echo de menos.
Why don't you go get some breakfast
¿Por qué no desayunas
and read a book or somethin' till Mama wakes up?
y lees o algo así hasta que se levante mamá?
NATHANIEL: What's the point of even reading a book?
Leer es un rollo.
Are you coming home tonight? It's Christmas movie marathon.
¿Vienes esta noche? Tenemos el maratón de pelis navideñas.
¿Estarás esta noche para las pelis?
Uh, yeah, it's... Tonight is movie marathon night, that's right. Um...
Ya... Esta noche es el maratón de pelis, es verdad.
I really wish I could be there with you, buddy.
Me encantaría poder estar allí con vosotros.
Uh, you know how much I love that.
Ya lo sabes.
Um, but I'm not gonna make it.
No voy a llegar a tiempo.
But I think I'll be back in the next day or so.
Creo que volveré a casa dentro de uno o dos días.
Yeah, we'll be in time for our ugly Christmas sweater party.
Justo a tiempo para la fiesta de jerséis garrulos.
You ready for that?
¿Estás listo?
Nathaniel?
¿Nathaniel?
(STUTTERS) Buddy?
¿Campeón?
NATHANIEL: It's okay if you can't come home for Christmas, Daddy.
No pasa nada si no puedes venir en Navidad.
We understand.
Lo entendemos.
Oh, boy, I'm... I tell you, I miss you so much.
No sabéis lo mucho que os echo de menos.
Dice que no pasa nada si no puedes ir en Navidad
Um, I'm gonna be there, buddy.
Claro que iré, tío.
I... You know I'm gonna be there, like I said, right?
Ya os dije que iría, ¿o no?
Um, I'm so happy to hear your voice.
Me alegra oír tu voz.
Daddy's gotta go, okay?
Tengo que dejarte, ¿vale?
I love you.
Te quiero.
NATHANIEL: Love you, Daddy.
Y yo a ti, papá.
I love you more.
Yo a ti más.
Bye-bye.
Adiós.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Yeah.
De nada.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Careful with it. Up top.
Esa es frágil, ponla arriba.
I was just getting used to this place, you know.
Le había empezado a coger cariño a este sitio.
KAZI: Yeah, well, now it's compromised.
Sí, pero ya no es seguro.
Estará vacío en unos minutos.
Hey. Hey.
Oye.
Quería hablar contigo.
¿Podemos hablar ahora?
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
No creo que estos idiotas hayan aprendido a signar
en las últimas 24 horas.
Vale, habla.
(EXHALES)
Hoy se nos ha ido de las manos.
¿Te das cuenta de lo peligroso que es?
Si seguimos yendo a por Ronin...
No podemos llamar la atención.
Solo espero que todo esto no llegue a oídos del Tío.
No.
No le haría gracia.
Si fuera mi padre,
¿también me cuestionarías?
Para tu padre, el equipo era lo primero.
A ver, ¿quién está al mando aquí?
(SIGHS)
Tú.
Exacto.
Encontrad a Clint Barton.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
(BARTON LAUGHS DRILY)
Menos mal que te llamaron Ojo de Halcón y no Oído de Halcón.
Block. Delete.
Bloquear. Eliminar.
Morning.
Buenos días.
WOMAN: What are you waiting for?
¿A quién esperáis?
Uh, you. You're the doctor, right?
A usted. Es la médica, ¿no?
I'm very busy.
Estoy muy liada.
Oh. Well... Really need this fixed.
Es que necesitamos arreglar esto.
Please?
Porfi.
Give me five minutes. Cash only.
Dadme cinco minutos. Solo acepto efectivo.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Told you we'd get it fixed.
Te dije que lo arreglaríamos.
What was most amazing though...
Aunque lo que más moló,
Better than anything we did in the middle of that crazy battle.
lo más alucinante de toda la persecución,
(MUFFLED) That little...
fue...
(CONTINUES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
-Was that... -(HEARING AID RUSTLES)
¿Lo...?
Was that out the whole time?
¿Lo llevabas apagado todo el rato?
Can I get more coffee, please?
¿Me trae otro café, por favor?
WAITER: Yeah, sure.
Claro.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Look, I know this may sound weird,
Mira, sé que te parecerá raro,
but I've dreamed of this for as long as I can remember.
pero llevo soñando con esto desde que tengo uso de razón.
My dad was fearless.
Mi padre no tenía miedo de nada.
And his whole life was about helping people.
Dedicó su vida a ayudar a los demás.
When I put that suit on, I thought, "This is it.
Cuando me puse el traje, pensé: "Ahora sí.
"This is the moment I become who I'm supposed to be."
"Ha llegado el momento de ser quien quiero ser".
I remember the day I thought the same thing.
Recuerdo el día que lo pensé yo.
You know, it's, uh... It comes with a price.
Que sepas... que tiene un precio.
What does?
¿El qué?
This life you wanna live.
La vida que quieres vivir.
To really help people.
Ayudar a los demás.
I mean, try to help people, anyway.
O intentarlo por lo menos.
Comes with a lot of sacrifices.
Supone muchos sacrificios.
And some things you'll lose... forever.
Y hay cosas que pierdes... para siempre.
Well, there's also things you gain,
Bueno, pero ganas otras.
like trick arrows and a cool costume.
Como flechas truco y un pedazo de traje.
Speaking of which.
Por cierto.
I've been thinking about your branding issue.
He estado pensando en el tema de tu imagen.
You need a more recognizable costume.
Necesitas un traje más reconocible.
Uh, you realize that my job for the last 20 years
Sabes que me he pasado los últimos 20 años
was to be not recognizable, right?
intentando que no me reconocieran, ¿no?
Well, you've officially failed at that.
Pues lo has hecho de pena.
Picture this... in purple.
Imagina esto... en morado.
Oh, wow.
-What's that on his head? -It's your head.
-¿Qué lleva en la cabeza? -Es tu cabeza.
Uh, wings. Like a hawk.
Alas. De halcón.
That's an "H" that's on your forehead. That's... for "Hawkeye."
Y una "H" en la frente. De "halcón".
Well, not happening.
Sigue soñando.
Okay. Um...
Vale.
What if it was all black? All black with a mask?
¿Y si fuera todo negro? Todo negro con una máscara.
Maybe a hood?
¿Y una capucha?
You can't say who Ronin is
No puedes decir quién es Ronin
because it's someone close to you, isn't it?
porque es amigo tuyo, ¿verdad?
It's your job to keep their secret.
Y tienes que guardarle el secreto.
There are several reasons why I'd never wear a flashy costume.
Hay muchas razones por las que nunca llevaría un traje tan llamativo.
My job is to be, number one, a ghost.
Número uno, mi trabajo es ser invisible.
Number two, my wife would divorce me if I put something like this on.
Número dos, mi mujer me pediría el divorcio si fuera con esas pintas.
Hmm?
And number three, uh...
Y número tres...
I'm not a role model.
No soy un modelo a seguir.
I'm sorry, Kate. I'm not a role model to anyone.
Lo siento, Kate, no soy un modelo a seguir para nadie.
Never have been.
Nunca lo he sido.
What? Yes, you are.
Claro que lo eres.
You are. You... You came here.
Sí que lo eres. Mira dónde estás.
You left your family at Christmas
Has renunciado a estar con tu familia en Navidad
because you thought some stranger was gonna get hurt.
porque creías que iban a hacer daño a una desconocida.
You stuck around even though I screwed up.
Y aquí estás, después de todas mis liadas.
And now you're stuck.
Y mira en la que te has metido.
Whether you like it or not,
Te guste o no,
the Tracksuits have connected us both to Ronin,
los Chándal creen que tenemos alguna relación con Ronin,
and it's pretty clear they're not just gonna drop this.
y está claro que no nos van a dejar en paz.
Well, that you are not wrong about.
Razón no te falta.
Not to mention the fact that my mom might be marrying a murderer.
Sin mencionar que el prometido de mi madre podría ser un asesino.
And then there's that.
Esa es otra.
As far as I'm concerned, we're in this together.
Por lo que a mí respecta, estamos juntos en esto.
I'm gonna need you to get that. My mom canceled my credit card.
Te toca pagar. Mi madre me ha anulado las tarjetas.
-Yeah, I got it. -Thank you.
-Sin problema. -Gracias.
All right. And look...
Vale. Estate alerta.
You're gonna have to name this dog, you know.
Y tendrás que ponerle nombre al perro.
Sure.
Ya.
(WHINES)
Little Ol' Caesar?
¿César el emperrador?
Dogfather?
¿Al Perrino?
Sir Dog of Pizza?
¿Sir Perro de Pizza?
Pizza Dog?
¿Perropizza?
(A MARSHMALLOW WORLD PLAYING)
All right, partner, let's get into it.
Vale, socio, hablemos de cosas serias.
You pick up on any tension between Maya and the hot guy, or was it just me?
¿Crees que hay tema entre Maya y el tío bueno, o es cosa mía?
His name's Kazi.
Se llama Kazi.
All right, so I take it these Tracksuit guys are into some pretty bad stuff?
Imagino que los Chándal estarán metidos en algo bastante turbio.
Yeah, bad stuff.
Sí, muy turbio.
You care to elaborate?
¿Quieres darme más detalles?
Not really.
La verdad es que no.
They started small, but grew.
Eran una banda pequeña, pero crecieron.
Or at least the guy at the top, he'll do anything to grow the operation.
El de arriba hará todo lo posible por expandir sus negocios.
I thought Maya was the boss.
Creía que Maya era la cabecilla.
No, there's someone above Maya.
No, hay alguien por encima.
Someone you don't wanna mess with.
Alguien a quien no nos conviene cabrear.
There's obviously bad blood with Ronin, right? Yeah.
Y está claro que le tienen ganas a Ronin.
Sí.
Ronin hit the supplier on the other side and then hit Tracksuit upper management.
Ronin acabó con su proveedor y con los altos mandos de los Chándal.
Sounds like a lot of drama.
Menudo dramón.
Which is why you should never get involved in organized crime.
Por eso no hay que meterse nunca en el crimen organizado.
Do you think that the Tracksuits were after anything else at that auction?
¿Crees que los Chándal fueron a la subasta a por algo más?
I don't know. I was pretty focused on Jack and Armand.
No sé. Estaba pendiente de Jack y Armand.
It's pretty upsetting to think there might be stuff
Me da bastante rabia pensar que hay cosas
from the Avengers Compound floating around out there.
de la base de los Vengadores circulando por ahí.
So, you still think Jack is involved somehow?
¿Crees que Jack está metido en todo esto?
Yes. There's too many coincidences.
Sí. Demasiadas coincidencias.
He was at the auction that night,
Estaba en la subasta,
and yesterday, he offered me a butterscotch.
y ayer me ofreció un tofe.
Not exactly a crime.
Menudo delito.
When I tried to stab his face to prove he was lying,
Y cuando intenté rajarle para demostrar que mentía,
he parried like a pro.
me esquivó sin despeinarse.
You tried to stab your mom's fiancé?
¿Intentaste rajar al prometido de tu madre?
Plus, he has everything to gain from Armand's death.
Además, sale ganando con la muerte de Armand.
The Jack thing, it's weird.
Lo de Jack huele mal.
I get it, but it's not exactly airtight.
Lo pillo. Pero no podemos demostrarlo.
Right.
Exacto.
Which is why we need more evidence.
Por eso necesitamos pruebas.
And why we're gonna sneak into my mom's penthouse.
Y por eso vamos a colarnos en casa de mi madre.
Wait, wait, wait, what?
Espera, ¿qué?
We can get into her company files.
Entraremos en sus archivos.
Bishop Security has a huge criminal database.
Seguridad Bishop tiene una base de datos de delincuentes.
There's gotta be info on the Tracksuits and Jack in there.
Tiene que haber algo sobre los Chándal y Jack.
Yeah.
Sí.
(DANCE OF THE SUGAR PLUM FAIRY PLAYING)
BARTON: You're sure no one's home, right?
Seguro que no hay nadie, ¿no?
Yes. Relax.
Sí, tranqui.
Come on.
Ven.
Jeez, this is a home?
Menudo casoplón.
Yeah. My, uh, great, great, great, great grandfather built the building.
Sí. Mi trastarabuelo construyó el edificio.
I tried to swing from that very chandelier and broke my arm.
Una vez usé la lámpara de liana y me rompí el brazo.
So, uh, yeah, pretty impressive family, all the way around.
Sí, somos una familia bastante impresionante.
Wow.
Impressive.
Impresionante.
SEGURIDAD BISHOP
KATE: So, from the home network,
Desde la red de casa
we should be able to get past the encryption with my mom's password.
deberíamos poder entrar con la contraseña de mi madre.
Yeah, I'm in the wrong business.
Me he equivocado de trabajo.
How'd you say Armand was killed?
¿Cómo dices que mataron a Armand?
Stabbed with a sword.
Con una espada.
BARTON: See if there's anything on Kazi.
Mira a ver si aparece Kazi.
KATE: Okay. Let's see.
Vale, a ver.
Here we go.
Vamos allá.
Okay, what's this company, Sloan Limited?
Vale, ¿qué empresa es esta? ¿Sloan Limited?
Kazi is an employee?
¿Kazi trabaja ahí?
BARTON: Wait, Sloan Limited, that sounds familiar.
Sloan Limited me suena mucho.
You think there's somethin' there?
¿Tendrá algo que ver?
I don't know.
No sé.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Maybe.
Puede.
KATE: Let me see what I can pull up on Jack.
A ver qué encontramos de Jack.
Crap.
Mierda.
Now there's an embedded hardware authentication.
Hay un autenticador de hardware.
And I've just been locked out.
Se ha bloqueado.
Se ha inhabilitado su cuenta
Clint?
¿Clint?
JACK: Don't move.
No te muevas.
(SWEET GINGERBREAD MAN PLAYING)
basada en los cómics de marvel
marvel studios presenta
Ojo de Halcón
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
---oOo---